Archie Battley

FREELANCE 3D ARTIST

Profile

I am a 3D Generalist and alumni from University of the Arts London, having received a First Class BA (Hons) Degree in 3D Computer Animation in 2023. I am extremely keen to start a career as a 3D Artist in a junior/graduate position in the creative industry.

I have over 8 years experience in using Adobe Creative Suite applications for design and video applications. I am also experienced with HTML, CSS and JS from my time as a web designer.

I have utilised a wide range of 3D & 2D production software during my studies as well as in my freelance professional career, including but not limited to: Maya, Blender,

Substance 3D Painter, ZBrush, Marvelous Designer, Unreal Engine, Reality Capture & Quixel Bridge. I have been able to use these skills on my personal work, a collaborative music video project with my peers as well as in my current freelance projects.

Here is a link to my portfolio website <u>www.archiebattley.com</u> where you will see my showreel and a selection of my projects.

Employment History

FREELANCE 3D ARTIST / PHOTOGRAPHER / VIDEO EDITOR, Racecar New Media Services, Remote Position

SEPTEMBER 2020 - PRESENT

- Creating optimised 3D Assets for use on web view integrations. (From ideation to subdivision modelling & texturing)
- Developing an integrated high-performance product configurator with the google model viewer API JavaScript library
- Filming, Editing & Video Production of interviews
- Photography & Video for automotive & marine clients: Talacrest Classic Ferrari, Mission Prestige, Rocketeer Cars, Neil Bainbridge Engineering & Broadblue Catamarans

FRONTEND DEVELOPER AND VIDEO PRODUCTION ASSISTANT, Racecar New Media Services, Shere

JUNE 2015 - SEPTEMBER 2020

- HTML and CSS Development for Webpage Styling and Responsive Content Presentation using Frameworks: Bootstrap 4 and React.js
- Website Graphics Design and Production for the Automotive Industry. Content management for mail campaigns and website stock editors.
- Film Editing/Video Production
- Improving Brand Identities and Social Media Presence for Clients
- Bespoke photography for classic automotive clients such as: Tim Samways Sporting & Historic Car Engineers, Shapecraft Classic Motor Bodies

Education

BA (Hons) 3D Computer Animation, University of the Arts London, London College of Communication, London

OCTOBER 2020 - MAY 2023

Graduated with First Class Honours

Godalming College, Godalming

SEPTEMBER 2016 - JUNE 2018

Graphic Design A Level

IT Level 3 BTEC

Geography A Level

Courses

Details

Cranleigh
United Kingdom
07925723711
archie@archiebattley.com

Links

archiebattley.com
LinkedIn
ArtStation

Skills

3D Modelling & Texturing
Blender, Maya, Zbrush, Substance
3D Painter, Forger, Nomad &
Reality Capture
Concepting & Illustration
Adobe Creative Suite
HTML, CSS & JavaScript
Branding & Web Design
Photoshop, Illustrator &
Premiere Pro

Hobbies

Motorsports, Photography and Filming, Movies, Music, Drawing & Painting, Video Games, Cycling

Duke of York Bronze Award, iDEA

JANUARY 2018 - FEBRUARY 2018

References

Ross Bowdler from Racecar

ross@racecar.com | 07776133268

Sam Roe from University of the Arts London

s.roe@lcc.arts.ac.uk

Internships

MOTION CAPTURE RUNNER (DAY WORK EXPERIENCE), Target3D, London

JULY 2023 - JULY 2023

- Assisting in Preparing Props for Motion Capture Using Markers
- Calibrating Props for Use in Motion Capture
- Providing Assistance to Talent in the Mocap Volume & Filming Reference Footage

CONSOLE 3D ART DEPARTMENT SHADOW (DAY WORK EXPERIENCE), Creative Assembly, Horsham

JUNE 2023 - JUNE 2023

- Shadowing the 3D Art Department Team Leads
- Learning About Edge Flow and Topology
- Taught about subdivision modelling in Blender
- Reporting to the UK Secretary of State for Culture, Media, and Sport